<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ScrollView</string>
    <string name="name">Sikanto Mandal was a ninth grader when he conceptualised and designed his unique swachhta cart. Sikanto Mandal’s early morning duties at school were a little different from that of other children who indulge in prayer and lessons. At the Jai Gurudev Sanstha School in Mathura, which provides subsidised education to underprivileged children, Sikanto and his classmates first cleaned their school premises.

    <b>\nA real childhood challenge\n</b>

        Usually girls swept the ground and boys collected the garbage and then dumped it. I observed how many of my friends hesitated to touch and lift the garbage with their bare hands. This set me thinking and urged me to innovate something that would solve our garbage collection woes, says Sikanto.

Sikanto then pitched the initial idea to his school teachers who further encouraged him to apply for the Inspire Awards. “To my surprise, my entry was selected and a sum of Rs 5,000 was transferred to my account to build my garbage-collecting device,” Sikanto adds\n.

The 15-year-old then spent one and a half months to construct his first elementary model of the manual, mobile garbage-collecting device. Designed after lots of trial and error, the initial model was mostly built using wooden parts from old furniture, bicycle brakes, chains, and other waste materials\n.

<b>\nConvenience is the differentiator\n\n</b>
    When questioned how his innovation differs from other existing garbage carts, Sikanto enthusiastically explains\n:

All the other devices in the market are mechanical and are run either on battery or fuel. My cart is completely manual, light-weight, and easy to operate. Sikanto’s mobile garbage-collecting device (for which he now holds patent) comes with simple yet unique fittings — a picker that aids in collecting garbage without touching it, a gripper and a handle which upon operating helps in easy dumping of the garbage without having to completely topple the cart\n.

I have also provided customised spaces in the cart where people collecting garbage can keep the broom, a water bottle and other waste materials they might pick on their way, adds the enterprising teenager. These added special features makes the cart ideal for use by municipal workers who toil hard to collect garbage in urban spaces such as parks, schools, etc\n.

Read more at: https://yourstory.com/2018/01/garbage-cart-innovation\n.



    </string>
</resources>
